	On screen prompt		Speaker	Dialog
T1_LOOK_UP	Pull right analog stick back to look up.		Leut Donatan	"Welcome to your first day in a real suit of armor, newblood Ransom.  I am Leut Donatan, and I'll be walking you through you equipment training.  You are operating a standard Light class combat armor suit.  You’ll notice that the real thing feels quite a bit different than the VR training you’ve already had.  We'll begin by calibrating your vision systems. Let’s start off by having you look up by pulling the right analog stick back."
T1_LOOK_DOWN	Push right analog stick forward to look down.		Leut Donatan	"Position calibrated.  Now if you will, please look down by pushing the right analog stick forwards."
T1_LOOK_LEFTRIGHT	Move right analog stick left and right to look left and look right.		Leut Donatan	Position calibrated.  Now let’s get you moving around in that armor.  You can turn by moving the right analog stick left or right. Please turn left and right now.
T1_MOVE_FORWARD	Push left analog stick forward to move forward.		Leut Donatan	"Good.  I’m now going to enable your suit’s locomotion systems.  The first thing I want you to do is get used to moving forward and back in your armor. To move forward, push the left analog stick forward. Move forward now, please."
T1_MOVE_BACK	Pull left analog stick back to move backward.		Leut Donatan	"Good.  To move back, pull the left analog stick back.  Move back now, please."
T1_MOVE_SIDEWAYS	Move left analog stick left and right to strafe left and strafe right.		Leut Donatan	"Easy enough.  Now, you can move sideways, or strafe, by moving the left analog stick left and right.  This will allow you to remain facing forward while performing evasive maneuvers.  Please strafe left and right now."
T1_JUMP	Press the L1 button to jump.		Leut Donatan	"By the way, if you didn’t notice, the degree to which you move the analog sticks determines how quickly you move and turn. Now, let’s see you test your suit’s jumping capabilities. To jump, press the L1 button."
T1_JETPACK	Hold the R1 button to fire jetpack thrusters.		Leut Donatan	"When you engage your jetpack, armor control systems automatically fire your jump mechanism to help get maximum boost.  Your jetpack uses armor energy and will cease to thrust once your energy is depleted. Skillful use of the jetpack is vital to the success and to the very survival of a warrior.  Press and hold the R1 button to use your jetpack.  Release it to stop."
T1_TOUCH_SWITCHES	Touch all 5 switches marked by white waypoints.		Leut Donatan	"Now, let's test what you’ve learned and have a little fun.  Inside the base are five control point switches. Each switch has a white waypoint so you can easily locate it. I want you to switch all five by simply touching them.  I’m dropping the force fields now so get ready… get set… go!"
T1_FOUR_TO_GO	Touch remaining 4 switches marked by white waypoints.			
T1_THREE_TO_GO	Touch remaining 3 switches marked by white waypoints.			
T1_TWO_TO_GO	Touch remaining 2 switches marked by white waypoints.			
T1_ONE_TO_GO	Touch final switch marked by white waypoint.			
T1_INTRO			Leut Donatan	"Good job, newblood.  Now let's review the various elements that make up your Heads-Up-Display, or HUD.  These readouts give you information about your armor, packs, weapons, and status.  Each part of the HUD will flash as I describe it to you."
T1_HEALTH_METER			Leut Donatan	"In the top left of your HUD, you will see three bars. The green one, at the top, shows the condition of  your armor.  The green bar will decrease in size as more damage is taken, and also changes from green to yellow to red as the damage increases.  If the bar completely disappears, then your armor has been damaged beyond repair and you will have to respawn in a fresh suit.  The blue bar below it shows your armor's energy reserve.  This energy is consumed by your jetpack, certain weapons, and even some packs as well.  The bar at the bottom shows the heat signature produced by your jetpack.  If it is high enough, you will become susceptible to lock-on by heat-seeking missiles."
T1_HUD_TEXT1	~FFFFFF~Real-time information is posted here…		Leut Donatan	"Real-time battle updates are posted in various locations in the your HUD.  The updates will include messages from other warriors, mission status information, remote equipment activation stats, and more."
T1_HUD_TEXT2	~FFFFFF~…here…			
T1_HUD_TEXT3	~FFFFFF~…and here.			
T1_SCOREBOARD			Leut Donatan	This box is used to display scoring information. The configuration of this readout will vary from mission type to mission type.  A timer is provided for time-critical missions.
T1_INVENTORY			Leut Donatan	This is your inventory display.  The top most icon shows you the type and quantity of grenades in your possession.  The icon at the bottom indicates the type and status of any pack you are carrying.  Other icons can be displayed in this area as well.
T1_RETICLE			Leut Donatan	"In the center of the screen you will see your reticle cluster. This displays aiming crosshairs for the current weapon as well as the available ammo count.  When you have an object centered within the reticle, your suit will attempt to acquire and display information about the target such as the range to target, target ID, and, for friendly assets, the state of repair for the target."
T1_MISSILE_LOCK			Leut Donatan	"This indicator provides information about heat seeking missiles.  When it is flashing yellow, a missile device is tracking your suit's heat signature and trying acquire a lock.  When it is flashing red, a missile has locked and launched."
T1_SUCCESS	Basic suit training complete.		Leut Donatan	"That's it for this phase of training, newblood.  We'll cover basic weapons in your next session."
T2_INTRO	Pick up any weapon.		Leut Donatan	Today we’ll be letting you get your hands on some weapons.  Feel free to run over any of the weapons scattered about the room to pick them up.  Ammo for each weapon is provided.
T2_DISKLAUNCHER	Press the L2 button to fire Spinfusor.		Leut Donatan	"This is the spinfusor. This little baby fires a disc-shaped charge that explodes on impact.  Many times when facing an enemy, it’s better to aim at the ground or walls around them to hit them with the splash damage.  Remember, with this weapon, ammo is limited.  Use the L2 button to fire."
T2_PLASMA	Press the L2 button to fire Plasma Rifle.		Leut Donatan	"OK, the weapon you have equipped now is the plasma rifle. This weapon fires superheated balls of plasma that explode on contact.  Much like the spinfusor, it relies heavily on splash damage.  The drawback to this weapon is the relatively slow speed of the projectile.  Direct hits with this weapon do a substantial amount of damage, however.  Use the L2 button to fire."
T2_GRENADELAUNCHER	Press the L2 button to fire Grenade Launcher.		Leut Donatan	This is the grenade launcher.  This weapon can be difficult to aim directly as the grenade fuse has to arm itself after it leaves the barrel.  This and its explosive damage radius makes it a good weapon for bouncing a few rounds around a blind corner to help clear out any opposition.  Lob a few grenades to get a feel for the weapon and its timing peculiarities.  Use the L2 button to fire.
T2_CHAINGUN	Hold the L2 button to fire Chaingun.		Leut Donatan	"This is the chaingun.  This weapon churns out a hail of explosive micro-flechettes that quickly chews up targets.  Its advantages are a high rate of fire, and substantial damage at close range.  On the down side, aiming is imprecise at longer range, and there is a barrel spin up delay between trigger press and onset of fire.  Test it out by pressing L2 to fire."
T2_BLASTER	Press the L2 button to fire Blaster.		Leut Donatan	"This is the blaster.  It has relatively unlimited ammo since it uses your suit’s power to fire pulsed energy rounds at a high rate of fire.  The blaster ignores personal shields, so it’s a good weapon to use against enemies with a shield pack.  You’ll also notice that its shots will ricochet off surfaces a few times before dissipating.  Fire it a few times by pressing the L2 button."
T2_SNIPERRIFLE	"Press the L2 button to fire Laser Rifle.
Use the directional button, and the R2 button to zoom.
Kill the training bot."		Leut Donatan	"The laser rifle is a sniping weapon, capable of severely damaging an enemy from a long distance.  When fired, it converts all of your armor's energy reserves into a single laser beam of destruction.  The strength of the beam is directly related to the amount of available energy at the moment of fire.  Snipers often also use energy packs to decrease to recovery time between shots.  Now use your zoom to target the training bot out on the platform, and take him out.  Fire by using the L2 button."
T2_CYCLE_WEAPONS	Press the â button to cycle to next weapon.		Leut Donatan	Press X to cycle to the next weapon.
T2_EXCHANGE_WEAPON	"Stand over the weapon you want.
Press the SELECT button to exchange weapon."		Leut Donatan	"The Light armor you are wearing only allows you to carry three weapons at a time. To pick up one of the weapons you haven't tried yet, stand on top of it and press the select button.  This will exchange your currently active weapon for the new one."
T2_GOTO_SNIPER_RANGE	"Follow waypoints up to sniper range.
Pick up Energy Pack.
Pick up Laser Rifle."		Leut Donatan	"Good.  I’m now placing a waypoint in your HUD.  Upon reaching it, you will need to use your jetpack to go up the chute and get the laser rifle and energy pack placed in the room up there.  The energy pack is one of several packs which either augment your armor's abilities or provide deployable remote equipment.  The energy pack automatically increases the rate at which your armor rebuilds energy reserves.  Energy packs do not have to be activated or deployed.  It functions as long as it is attached to your armor."
T2_USE_ZOOM	"Hold the R2 button to zoom.
Use directional button UP to increase zoom factor.
Use directional button DOWN to decrease zoom factor."		Leut Donatan	"From this position, you will be able to see a targeting bot in the distance.  To get a closer look at the bot, put him within your sights and press and hold the R2 button.  This engages your zoom.  Dpad Up and Down adjust your zoom factor. "
T2_AUTOLOCK	"Switch weapons (press the â button).
Go outside and target training bot.
Press the ü button to engage target lock."		Leut Donatan	"Alright.  Now it’s time to learn a little bit about your automatic targeting systems. These systems will help you to acquire and hit targets with your weapons. To lock onto an enemy, get them near the center of your targeting reticle and hit the Square button. You will notice at this point that you automatically turn to face in the direction of the enemy you are locked on to and your aiming system is locked onto them as well; so all you need to do is pull the trigger.  There is a targeting bot outside.  You will need to go out there and lock onto the bot.  Your weapons will be disabled until you do so.  Once you have locked on, destroy the bot and pick up his ammo box to complete this part of your training.  The lock on system does not work with the Laser rifle, so switch to another weapon if you still have the Laser Rifle equipped and I’ll drop the force fields."
T2_KILL_BOT	"Kill the training bot.
Pick up dropped ammo box."		Leut Donatan	"OK, you have him locked.  I’m releasing your fire button, so go ahead and take him out.  Don't forget to grab his ammo box by running over it."
T2_WELLDONE	Basic weapon training complete.		Leut Donatan	Well done.  This concludes training module 2.
T3_REPAIR_PATCH	"Go to waypoint.
Pick up Repair Patch.
Pick up Repair Kit."		Leut Donatan	"OK newblood, you have been outfitted in Heavy class armor for this portion of your training.  It looks like your armor integrity is a bit low, so let's take care of that.  Repair kits and repair patches are used for in-the-field repairs.  All you have to do is run over one, and limited repairs will begin automatically.  Run over the ones I have waypointed in your HUD."
T3_FRAG_GRENADE	Press the Ç button to throw Basic Grenade.		Leut Donatan	"Now, on to grenades.  Grenades come in 4 flavors.  Select which type you want to carry when choosing your inventory.  In normal situations you can only carry one type at a time, but for the purposes of training you have been equipped with 1 of each type.  First, is the basic grenade, also known as the hand grenade.  It explodes and sends a blast of small metal fragments in all directions.  Throw one now using the triangle button."
T3_FLARE_GRENADE	Press the Ç button to throw Flare Grenade.		Leut Donatan	"Next up we have flares.  The flare burns brightly when released and may be used as a countermeasure against heat-seeking missiles.  You can even throw flares to deflect missiles when piloting vehicles.  Again, use the triangle button to throw a flare now."
T3_CONCUSSION_GRENADE	Press the Ç button to throw Concussion Grenade.		Leut Donatan	"The next grenade is the concussion grenade.  It does not break into fragments like the hand grenade, and does not cause damage.  Instead, it causes a severe but localized concussive force which is sufficient to knock a weapon out of an enemy's hands.  It will also dislodge packs and can even extricate a flag from an enemy's back.  Like other grenades, throw with the triangle button.  Go ahead and toss one."
T3_MINE	Press the Ç button to deploy Mine.		Leut Donatan	"Last but not least, we have mines.  These can be useful in a variety of situations.  When deployed, they slightly burrow themselves into the ground before the charge is armed.  Once armed, a mine will detonate when its proximity field is entered, or if it is subjected to a shock from a projectile or explosion.  Mines will fail to deploy if placed too close to other mines or on or against other equipment.  These babies do some damage, so keep your eyes peeled for them in combat situations.  You can place a mine by pressing the Triangle button. Do this now.  And try not to step on your own mine once it has deployed."
T3_MORTAR	"Press the â button to cycle to Fusion Mortar.
Press the L2 button to fire Fusion Mortar.
Destroy turrets."		Leut Donatan	"OK, now on to some heavy weapons training.  First up we have the fusion mortar.  The mortar is a devastating weapon; but its projectiles travels in an arc, similar to the grenade launcher, but with much more punch.  Heavy armors are the only ones beefy enough to handle these babies.  OK, equip your mortar and see what you can do with it.  There are some AA turrets scattered around.  See how many you can bust up."
T3_SWITCH_TO_MISSILE	Press the â button to cycle to Missile Launcher when ready.		Leut Donatan	Switch to the missile launcher when you are done.
T3_MISSILELAUNCHER	"Fire missiles at turrets.
Fire all missiles to complete training."		Leut Donatan	"The missile launcher fires a heat seeking missile that can lock onto larger enemy assets, such as turrets, and also enemy armors with a high enough heat signature. Your armor provides visual and audio cues as you track and lock onto targets.  You are not able to fire the missile launcher when it is not locked on.  Try taking out some of those AA turrets.  Fire all missiles to complete the exercise. "
T3_COMPLETE	Advanced weapon training complete.		Leut Donatan	Good job. You have completed this training module.
T4_GOTO_REPAIR_PACK	"Go to waypoint.
Pick up Repair Pack."		Leut Donatan	"OK newblood, we have a lot to do today, so let’s get busy.  The first thing you’re gonna need is a repair pack.  There’s one placed right up the hill.  I have it waypointed for you so go ahead and get it. "
T4_SKI_TO_BUNKER	"Ski down to waypoint.
Hold the L1 button to ski."		Leut Donatan	"Good. Now I want you to ""ski"" to the small bunker I've waypointed for you.  To ""ski"", head down the hill and hold the jump button, which is L1.  You will notice that you pick up speed as you travel.  ""Skiing"" can be used in conjunction with the jetpack to travel more efficiently."
T4_REPAIR_INVEN	"Press the é button to activate Repair Pack.
Aim at inventory station and hold the L2 button.
Repair station to full functionality."		Leut Donatan	"Alright.  In this bunker you will see an inventory station.  This station is damaged and is non-functional.  You are going to change that.  Activate your repair pack by pressing the CIRCLE button.  This will cause your current weapon to be replaced by a repair tool which is provided by the repair pack.  Now get close to the station and place your targeting crosshairs on it.  Press and hold the fire button, which is L2, to begin the repair process."
T4_SHIELD_PACK	"Use Inventory menu (press the START button).
Equip a Shield Pack (use directional button and the â button).
Step onto inventory station pad."		Leut Donatan	"OK, now go into your inventory setup and select a shield pack.  Once you have done that, go and get one from the inventory station.  The shield pack provides extra protection against enemy fire at the expense of your suit's energy reserve.  When the shield is active, the shield pack icon will flash and you will hear an audible cue.  Remember, if your energy runs out, the shield will deactivate.  Use it by pressing the circle button."
T4_USE_SHIELD_PACK	"Step off inventory station pad.
Press the é button to activate Shield Pack."			
T4_USE_INVEN	"Use Inventory menu (press the START button).
Equip a Medium armor.
Equip a Remote Station Pack."		Leut Donatan	"Good. Now, enter your inventory menu and set your loadout to Medium armor with a remote station as your pack.  Your weapons systems will be disabled for the purposes of this exercise, so your weapon choice doesn’t matter.  Once you have set your loadout, step onto the inventory station platform."
T4_WRONG_LOADOUT	Wrong loadout selected.  Try again.		Leut Donatan	Wrong loadout selected.  Try again.
T4_DEPLOY_INVEN	Press the é button to deploy Remote Station at waypoint.		Leut Donatan	"Now you're going to deploy the remote station.  Head on over to the new waypoint in your HUD.  Look directly at the point where you want to attempt to deploy the remote station, and then press the circle button.  Note that the station will not deploy if the location at which you are aiming is too close or too far.  There are other restrictions when remote deployment.  Your suit's on-board systems will keep you informed."
T4_USE_DEPLOYED_INVEN	"Use Inventory menu (press the START button).
Equip a Missile Barrel.
Use Remote Station to get selected loadout."		Leut Donatan	"Good.  Remote inventory stations have everything the base stations have with two key exceptions.  First, you cannot aquire get a remote station from a remote station.  And second, you cannot change armor type at a remote station.  Used properly, remote stations can be valuable field assets for yourself and teammates.  Deploying that station left you without a pack, so let’s get a new one.  This time, I want you to select a missile barrel pack.  These barrels can be use to change out barrel types on base turrets.  Go ahead and get the barrel now."
T4_SWAP_TURRET_BARREL	"Go to waypoint.
Aim at base turret.
Press the é button to deploy Missile Barrel."		Leut Donatan	"OK, now I want you to go the turret I’ve waypointed.  Approach it, target it, and press the circle button to swap barrels."
T4_DEPLOY_TURRET	"Use Inventory menu (press the START button).
Equip a Remote Turret Pack and use Remote Station.
Press the é button to deploy Remote Turret."		Leut Donatan	"Good job.  Now, while we are on the subject of turrets, go into your inventory screen and select a remote turret as your pack.  Once you have done that, get one from the remote station.  Remote turrets can be deployed almost any place you can reach.  Each team has a limited number of these and they cannot be placed within close proximity of each other.  Once you've got one, go ahead and deploy it by pressing the circle button."
T4_DEPLOY_SATCHEL	"Use Inventory menu (press the START button).
Equip a Satchel Charge Pack and use Remote Station.
Press the é button to deploy Satchel Charge."		Leut Donatan	"Now for some serious explosives.  A satchel charge pack is a remotely detonated, high explosive munition. Get one from the remote station, and then press the circle button to deploy it.  Remember, just press the cirlce button one time to deploy, got it?"
T4_ACTIVATE_SATCHEL	"Move off a safe distance from deployed charge.
Press the é button to detonate Satchel Charge."		Leut Donatan	"Once a satchel charge is deployed, it takes a moment to arm itself.  Now, even in Heavy armor, you do not want to experience a satchel detonation at close range.  I suggest you move off a safe distance.  When ready, press the circle button to trigger the charge."
T4_DEPLOY_SENSOR	"Use Inventory menu (press the START button).
Equip a Remote Sensor Pack and use Remote Station.
Press the é button to deploy Remote Sensor."		Leut Donatan	Ok.  Now it’s time to learn about remote sensors.  All sensors extend the firing range for all types of turrets.  Remote sensors can be placed in the field to strengthen turret defenses in selected areas.  Two sensors units come in a pack.  Using the circle button will deploy one.  Do this now. 
T4_COMPLETE	Advanced equipment training complete.		Leut Donatan	That's it for advanced equipment training.  Get some rest.  We'll be working with vehicles next.
T5_INTRO			Leut Donatan	"Newblood, this portion of your training will cover familiarization with the various vehicles used in combat situations.  When used wisely, vehicles may mean the difference between victory and defeat on the field of battle. "
T5_GET_IN_VEHICLE	"Use jetpack to fly into seat.
(Automatic upon vehicle creation.)"		Leut Donatan	"To enter the vehicle, use your jetpack to fly into the seat."
T5_WRONG_SEAT	Wrong seat.  Press the L1 button to jump out.		Leut Donatan	"Wrong seat, newblood.  You're supposed to be driving.  Use the jump button to get out."
T5_JUMP_DISABLED	Proceed to waypoint before exiting vehicle.			
T5_JUMP_OUT	Press the L1 button to jump out of vehicle.		Leut Donatan	"OK, you are within range of the next station.  Use L1 to jump from the vehicle and make your way towards the station."
T5_GET_GRAV_CYCLE	"Use Vehicle menu (press the START button).
Select ""Mongoose"" Grav Cycle.
Step onto vehicle station platform."		Leut Donatan	The first vehicle we will cover is the Mongoose grav cycle.  Go into your menu by pressing the start button. Then go to the tab marked vehicle.  From here you move through the menu choices to select the Mongoose.  Then get the cycle by stepping onto the vehicle station platform.
T5_INFO_GRAV_CYCLE	"Follow waypoints.
Press the R1 button to boost.
Press the Ç button to throw Flare Grenades."		Leut Donatan	"The Mongoose is a light, unarmed ground vehicle.  It's fast, but hard to keep under control.  The vehicle HUD is slightly different from your suit HUD.  Underneath your armor condition indicator is another green bar indicating the condition of the vehicle you are in.  Below this is a blue bar indicating the vehicle's available auxilary boost energy.  Use your jet button, R1, to boost.  This will increase the speed of your vehicle.  Much like armor, the left analog stick will move your vehicle and the right analog stick controls turning.  If you have flares equipped, the triangle button will throw them.  Try out the Mongoose.  I have set a series of waypoints heading to the next vehicle station.  Follow them."
T5_GET_TRANSPORT	"Use Vehicle menu (press the START button).
Select ""Piltdown"" Transport.
Step onto vehicle station platform."		Leut Donatan	"OK, go into your vehicle menu and select the Piltdown transport, then go ahead and get one from the station."
T5_INFO_TRANSPORT	Fly to waypoint.		Leut Donatan	"The Piltdown is the workhorse of the tribal fleet, capable of carrying a pilot plus 4 armors.  You will notice it also has a rear-mounted turret.  This is automated, so all you have to do is worry about getting your people to where they need to be.  The Piltdown is pretty slow and sluggish to manuever.  Go ahead and follow the waypoint to the next station."
T5_GET_BOMBER	"Use Vehicle menu (press the START button).
Select ""Hammer"" Bomber.
Step onto vehicle station platform."		Leut Donatan	"OK, go into your vehicle menu and select the Hammer bomber.  Then head over to the station and get one."
T5_INFO_BOMBER	"Fly to waypoint.
Hold the R2 button to see bomb view.
Press the L2 button to drop bombs."		Leut Donatan	"The Hammer can rain serious trouble down on an opponent.  Use your fire button to drop bombs.  In order to aim, hold the zoom button, or R2, to switch to the bomb view.  You can practice on the turrets and bunkers on the ground as you make your way to the next station."
T5_GET_SCOUT	"Use Vehicle menu (press the START button).
Select ""Dingo"" Fighter.
Step onto vehicle station platform."		Leut Donatan	The Dingo fighter is a lightly armored single seat flying vehicle.  It is equipped with dual wingtip blasters and is a pretty versatile craft.  Use the vehicle menu to select the Dingo now and step on the vehicle pad to get one. 
T5_INFO_SCOUT	"Fly to waypoint.
Press the L2 button to fire blasters."		Leut Donatan	"OK, now take the Dingo to the next waypoint.  Feel free to try out the blasters.  The Dingo can be invaluable as both a support and recon unit.  Many cappers use them to get to and from enemy bases quickly. "
T5_COMPLETE	Vehicle training complete.		Leut Donatan	"Good job, that's it for vehicle training, newblood."
T5_WRONG_VEHICLE	"Wrong vehicle selected.
Vehicle station deactivated."			
M01_BRIEFING	"~FFFFFF~Up and at 'em, newbloods.

Painful as it is to call you washouts soldiers, I am forced to admit you can walk and talk at the same time.  So, today I'm turning you back over to Leut Donatan for the next stage of your training.

During this next series of exercises, you will be equipped with training weapons and armor.  You'll use your jets for real.  Your weapons will look and feel like the real thing.  You will see the explosions.  You will feel it when a buddy shoots you.  And you may even go down with a few bruises.  The only thing hurt today, though, will be your pride.

We will begin with a simple contest called Deathmatch.  Fortunately, the rules are very simple.  Frag anybody you see.  And remember, everybody else is gunning for you, so keep moving.

All participants will be issued the same equipment.  There will be no inventory stations available in this scenario.  However, there are alternate weapons, ammo, and packs located about the training area.  To avoid running out of ammo, keep an eye open for ammo boxes dropped by fragged players.  This may not be a problem for any of you, though, as it is unlikely that any of you worms will be able to maintain your armor integrity long enough to run out of ammo.

You may see some Starwolf out there.  Ur-Lieutenant Kestrelson has a training cadre here as well. The Leut and I would be pleased if a Blood Eagle got the high score today."		Khanjar Zane	"Up and at 'em, newbloods.

Painful as it is to call you washouts soldiers, I am forced to admit you can walk and talk at the same time.  So, today I'm turning you back over to Leut Donatan for the next stage of your training.

During this next series of exercises, you will be equipped with training weapons and armor.  You'll use your jets for real.  Your weapons will look and feel like the real thing.  You will see the explosions.  You will feel it when a buddy shoots you.  And you may even go down with a few bruises.  The only thing hurt today, though, will be your pride.

We will begin with a simple contest called Deathmatch.  Fortunately, the rules are very simple.  Frag anybody you see.  And remember, everybody else is gunning for you, so keep moving.

All participants will be issued the same equipment.  There will be no inventory stations available in this scenario.  However, there are alternate weapons, ammo, and packs located about the training area.  To avoid running out of ammo, keep an eye open for ammo boxes dropped by fragged players.  This may not be a problem for any of you, though, as it is unlikely that any of you worms will be able to maintain your armor integrity long enough to run out of ammo.

You may see some Starwolf out there.  Ur-Lieutenant Kestrelson has a training cadre here as well. The Leut and I would be pleased if a Blood Eagle got the high score today."
M01_INTRO			Leut Donatan	"Good morning, recruits.  Deathmatch is a free-for-all combat simulation.  There are no teams, everyone is a target.  You will find other weapons, packs, and ammo scattered around the training grounds.  Also remember to scavenge ammo from other players by grabbing the ammo boxes they drop.  Your goal is to achieve as many kills or frags as possible, using all the weapons and skill at your disposal.  You need a score of 15 to pass this exercise.  "
M01_SUCCESS	Mission success.		Leut Donatan	"Good job, newblood... Ransom, isn't it?  Well, don't let it go to your head."
M01_FAIL	Mission failure.		Leut Donatan	"Well, newblood, I’m afraid you didn’t make the cut this time. You can try again tomorrow."
M01_DEBRIEF	"~FFFFFF~The Leut says you wet-noses all did pretty well out there today.  Respectably, even.  I'm shocked to hear it.  However, I now expect you'll do even better tomorrow.

Remember: when you face the Hordes, it won't be a game.

Dismissed."		Khanjar Zane	"The Leut says you wet-noses all did pretty well out there today.  Respectably, even.  I'm shocked to hear it.  However, I now expect you'll do even better tomorrow.

Remember: when you face the Hordes, it won't be a game.

Dismissed."
M02_BRIEFING	"~FFFFFF~Listen up, newbloods!

Today’s exercise is more complicated than the last one, more like what you'll get with real action.  It's an ""asset liberation"" exercise known as Capture the Flag.

You will be split into two teams: Storm and Inferno.  Each team has a base containing a flag.  The goal of this exercise is simple enough, even for your limited intellects.  Grab the other team’s flag, make your way back to your team’s base, and touch their flag to your own.  That's a cap.  Got that?  And stop the enemy from doing the same thing with your flag, although that should be obvious even to snails like you.

We'll put waypoints on your armor's HUD so you can locate both teams' flags and bases.  Furthermore, your teammates will be designated by green indicators, while enemies will be red.  That's standard combat armor HUD behavior and you'll use it in real battles as well.

While the desire to win should be enough motivation even for you washouts, here's a little extra incentive.  First team to get six caps before time runs out gets a week of steak dinners.  Klef-deer venison raised right here on this world.  Losers get a week of KP.

Happy capping, newbloods."		Khanjar Zane	"Listen up, newbloods!

Today’s exercise is more complicated than the last one, more like what you'll get with real action.  It's an ""asset liberation"" exercise known as Capture the Flag.

You will be split into two teams: Storm and Inferno.  Each team has a base containing a flag.  The goal of this exercise is simple enough, even for your limited intellects.  Grab the other team’s flag, make your way back to your team’s base, and touch their flag to your own.  That's a cap.  Got that?  And stop the enemy from doing the same thing with your flag, although that should be obvious even to snails like you.

We'll put waypoints on your armor's HUD so you can locate both teams' flags and bases.  Furthermore, your teammates will be designated by green indicators, while enemies will be red.  That's standard combat armor HUD behavior and you'll use it in real battles as well.

While the desire to win should be enough motivation even for you washouts, here's a little extra incentive.  First team to get six caps before time runs out gets a week of steak dinners.  Klef-deer venison raised right here on this world.  Losers get a week of KP.

Happy capping, newbloods."
M02_INTRO			Leut Donatan	"OK, newbloods.  The Khanjar has briefed you on the particulars of today's exercise.  Locate the waypoints on the flags.  Then get busy!"
M02_HALFWAY			Leut Donatan	That's three caps for team Storm.  You're halfway there!
M02_ONE_TO_GO			Leut Donatan	"Nice work out there, Team Storm.  Only one more cap to go!"
M02_TAUNT_1			Leut Donatan	"Pick it up, newblood Ransom.  Your opposition is making this look easy."
M02_TAUNT_2			Khanjar Zane	"Get it together, washout, unless you want that KP!"
M02_SUCCESS			Leut Donatan	Well done.  The Khanjar is shaping you up nicely.  I look forward to seeing your progress in future exercises.
M02_FAIL			Leut Donatan	"You need to put more effort into teamwork, newbloods.  Tomorrow's another day."
M02_DEBRIEF	"~FFFFFF~How's that steak, newblood Ransom?  Taste good?  Well, you earned it.  Good job out there today.

Don't forget to slip some to your buddies stuck on KP.  And if you tell anyone I said that, your butt will be on sentry duty until this sun goes nova.  You got that?  Good!

As you were."		Khanjar Zane	"How's that steak, newblood Ransom?  Taste good?  Well, you earned it.  Good job out there today.

Don't forget to slip some to your buddies stuck on KP.  And if you tell anyone I said that, your butt will be on sentry duty until this sun goes nova.  You got that?  Good!

As you were."
M03_BRIEFING	"~FFFFFF~Good morning, cadets.  Khanjar Zane is on another assignment, so I will handle the briefing.

Today's exercise is a different twist on the asset collection exercises you've been running.  We call it Hunters.  Each of you starts in possession of one flag.  You accumulate additional flags by picking them up in the field.  When you are fragged, all flags in your possesion fall into the field and may be picked up by other cadets.  Your objective is to collect as many flags as possible and return them to the Nexus, where they will be traded for points.  A waypoint marks the Nexus.

Note that you get more points the more flags you bring to the Nexus in a single visit.  You can not win by simply bringing two or three flags in at a time.

You will all be issued Light armor and a standard loadout of a spinfusor, chaingun, blaster, fragmentation grenades, and even an energy pack.  As with Deathmatch, other equipment may be found scattered across the mission area.

The winners of this exercise will receive a three-day pass to the Unitech settlement at Monolith Falls, reasonable expenses paid.

Suit up and grab your gear.  I'll see you on the field in ten."		Leut Donatan	"Good morning, cadets.  Khanjar Zane is on another assignment, so I will handle the briefing.

Today's exercise is a different twist on the asset collection exercises you've been running.  We call it Hunters.  Each of you starts in possession of one flag.  You accumulate additional flags by picking them up in the field.  When you are fragged, all flags in your possession fall into the field and may be picked up by other cadets.  Your objective is to collect as many flags as possible and return them to the Nexus, where they will be traded for points.  A waypoint marks the Nexus.

Note that you get more points the more flags you bring to the Nexus in a single visit.  You can not win by simply bringing two or three flags in at a time.

You will all be issued Light armor and a standard loadout of a spinfusor, chaingun, blaster, fragmentation grenades, and even an energy pack.  As with Deathmatch, other equipment may be found scattered across the mission area.

The winners of this exercise will receive a three-day pass to the Unitech settlement at Monolith Falls, reasonable expenses paid.

Suit up and grab your gear.  I'll see you on the field in ten."
M03_INTRO_3000			Leut Donatan	"Take a moment to orient yourselves.  This exercise rewards the tactics of opportunism and patience.  I recommend you not dash in with one flag at a time.  Gather several before making a run at the Nexus.  You need 3000 points to pass this exercise.  Get moving.  You are the hunter, but you are also the prey."
M03_INTRO_2500			Leut Donatan	"Take a moment to orient yourselves.  This exercise rewards the tactics of opportunism and patience.  I recommend you not dash in with one flag at a time.  Gather several before making a run at the Nexus.  You need 2500 points to pass this exercise.  Get moving.  You are the hunter, but you are also the prey."
M03_INTRO_2000			Leut Donatan	"Take a moment to orient yourselves.  This exercise rewards the tactics of opportunism and patience.  I recommend you not dash in with one flag at a time.  Gather several before making a run at the Nexus.  You need 2000 points to pass this exercise.  Get moving.  You are the hunter, but you are also the prey."
M03_INTRO_1000			Leut Donatan	"Take a moment to orient yourselves.  This exercise rewards the tactics of opportunism and patience.  I recommend you not dash in with one flag at a time.  Gather several before making a run at the Nexus.  You need 1000 points to pass this exercise.  Get moving.  You are the hunter, but you are also the prey."
M03_INTRO_750			Leut Donatan	"Take a moment to orient yourselves.  This exercise rewards the tactics of opportunism and patience.  I recommend you not dash in with one flag at a time.  Gather several before making a run at the Nexus.  You need 750 points to pass this exercise.  Get moving.  You are the hunter, but you are also the prey."
M03_INTRO_500			Leut Donatan	"Take a moment to orient yourselves.  This exercise rewards the tactics of opportunism and patience.  I recommend you not dash in with one flag at a time.  Gather several before making a run at the Nexus.  You need 500 points to pass this exercise.  Get moving.  You are the hunter, but you are also the prey."
M03_INTRO			Leut Donatan	"This exercise rewards the tactics of opportunism and patience.  I recommend you not dash in with one flag at a time.  Gather several before making a run at the Nexus.  You need 250 points to pass this exercise.  Get moving.  You are the hunter, but you are also the prey."
M03_SUCCESS			Leut Donatan	"Good work, Ransom.  I'm impressed.  Enjoy Monolith Falls.  I hear the miners there are friendly people."
M03_FAIL			Leut Donatan	"Work on your patience, cadet Ransom.  You'll get another chance."
M03_DEBRIEF	"~FFFFFF~Hey, newblood.

I hear your group is taking the shuttle to Monolith for some R and R, huh?  Well, well.  Congratulations.  

Don't have too much fun, though.  When you get back, we're going back into the field with a vengeance.  Can't let you washouts get soft, after all."		Khanjar Zane	"Hey, newblood.

I hear your group is taking the shuttle to Monolith for some R and R, huh?  Well, well.  Congratulations.  

Don't have too much fun, though.  When you get back, we're going back into the field with a vengeance.  Can't let you washouts get soft, after all."
M04_BRIEFING	"~FFFFFF~C'mon, newbloods, move it!  Get into your teams.

We start a new exercise today:  Capture and Hold.  There are three control points spread across the training area.  Your objective is to capture these points and keep them in your team's possession as long as possible.

You capture a control point for your team simply by touching it.  Once you do so, it belongs to your squad until an enemy touches it.  Your team gets 1 point per second you hold a control point, but only after you have held said objective for 10 seconds.  Do we all understand this, or do I need to speak more slowly?

All right.  I have decided to be nice today.  There are inventory stations in each team's main base so you can customize your loadouts.  You are advised to take advantage of this.

Winning team gets rack time all day tomorrow.  The losers get to move shipping crates.  Me?  I get to remind the losers of my displeasure...  All day long."		Khanjar Zane	"C'mon, newbloods, move it!  Get into your teams.

We start a new exercise today:  Capture and Hold.  There are three control points spread across the training area.  Your objective is to capture these points and keep them in your team's possession as long as possible.

You capture a control point for your team simply by touching it.  Once you do so, it belongs to your squad until an enemy touches it.  Your team gets 1 point per second you hold a control point, but only after you have held said objective for 10 seconds.  Do we all understand this, or do I need to speak more slowly?

All right.  I have decided to be nice today.  There are inventory stations in each team's main base so you can customize your loadouts.  You are advised to take advantage of this.

Winning team gets rack time all day tomorrow.  The losers get to move shipping crates.  Me?  I get to remind the losers of my displeasure...  All day long."
M04_INTRO			Leut Donatan	First team to amass 1000 points wins.  Capture and hold those objectives!  Let's move!
M04_INTRO_900			Leut Donatan	First team to amass 900 points wins.  Capture and hold those objectives!  Let's move!
M04_INTRO_800			Leut Donatan	First team to amass 800 points wins.  Capture and hold those objectives!  Let's move!
M04_INTRO_750			Leut Donatan	First team to amass 750 points wins.  Capture and hold those objectives!  Let's move!
M04_INTRO_700			Leut Donatan	First team to amass 700 points wins.  Capture and hold those objectives!  Let's move!
M04_INTRO_600			Leut Donatan	First team to amass 600 points wins.  Capture and hold those objectives!  Let's move!
M04_INTRO_500			Leut Donatan	First team to amass 500 points wins.  Capture and hold those objectives!  Let's move!
M04_SUCCESS			Leut Donatan	"Nice work out there, Ransom.  Good teamwork."
M04_FAIL			Leut Donatan	"Not good, newblood Ransom.  That performance did not impress.  Looks like you still have a lot to learn.  "
M04_DEBRIEF	"~FFFFFF~Attention!  All right.

Some of you, like Ransom and his squad here, get to relax tomorrow.  Good for them.

The rest of you washouts, however, are my meat.  We're up at 0400 for some heavy lifting.  And let me tell you right now, meat, I expect cheerful attitudes out there.  Shipping crates are your friends, and you will move them with a smile on your face and a song in your heart.

Dismissed!"		Khanjar Zane	"Ten-shun!  All right.

Some of you, like Ransom and his squad here, get to relax tomorrow.  Good for them.

The rest of you washouts, however, are my meat.  We're up at 0400 for some heavy lifting.  And let me tell you right now, meat, I expect cheerful attitudes out there.  Shipping crates are your friends, and you will move them with a smile on your face and a song in your heart.

Dismissed!"
M05_BRIEFING	"~FFFFFF~Fall in, newbloods.

We're going to pull out all the stops today.  And no, that does not mean guarding crates again.

Direct your feeble brains to the CTF exercise we ran last month.  Today we will run another CTF exercise, but with full access to inventory and even limited access to vehicle stations.  Mongooses and Dingoes are the only vehicles available for this mission.  Anything further would be wasted on scroff like you.

Remember:  Medium suits cannot pilot the Mongoose.  Heavies cannot pilot anything.  Try not to crash into your buddies.

Today you get to pretend you are real soldiers.  Do not let it go to your heads.  I have yet to be convinced this entire training program is not some hideous mistake."		Khanjar Zane	"Fall in, newbloods.

We're going to pull out all the stops today.  And no, that does not mean guarding crates again.

Direct your feeble brains to the CTF exercise we ran last month.  Today we will run another CTF exercise, but with full access to inventory and even limited access to vehicle stations.  Mongooses and Dingoes are the only vehicles available for this mission.  Anything further would be wasted on scroff like you.

Remember:  Medium suits cannot pilot the Mongoose.  Heavies cannot pilot anything.  Try not to crash into your buddies.

Today you get to pretend you are real soldiers.  Do not let it go to your heads.  I have yet to be convinced this entire training program is not some hideous mistake."
M05_INTRO			Leut Donatan	"Morning, cadets.  The Khanjar has briefed you.  The team that scores six caps in the time allotted wins.  Let's see what you can do. "
M05_SUCCESS			Leut Donatan	"Good job, cadet Ransom.  You and your squad are examples of what this accelerated training program can produce."
M05_FAIL			Leut Donatan	"Cadet Ransom, you've done well up until today.  I'm going to assume you are having a bad day and let you try this exercise again tomorrow.  Dismissed."
M05_DEBRIEF	"~FFFFFF~Ransom, front and center.

I want you to take a squad out and position a guard around the transport crates at the Western Perimeter Tower.  Make sure you look alert.  Take live weapons and battle-ready armor.  This is not a drill.  We'll relieve you in six hours.  Move out."		Khanjar Zane	"Ransom, front and center.

I want you to take a squad out and position a guard around the transport crates at the Western Perimeter Tower.  Make sure you look alert.  Take live weapons and battle-ready armor.  This is not a drill.  We'll relieve you in six hours.  Move out."
M06_BRIEFING	"~FFFFFF~Sit down, newbloods.  And don't look so shocked.  Your training is over.  It has been for weeks.  We've been pushing you through extra drills to sharpen your skills.

You are no longer cadets.  You are soldiers.  And now it's time for you to prove it.

A little over seven hours ago, a BioDerm assault flotilla entered the system.  Right now, Derm reavers are dropping into key locations across Gamma Serpentis IV.  They think we're guarding something important here, something besides a bunch of steak-filled refrigerator crates.  We want them to continue to think that.

From the initial reports, it's clear we are vastly outnumbered.  Our plan is to hit the Derms hard and not give an inch.

Ransom!  I need you to volunteer for a solo mission!  There’s a small unoccupied base right in the path of one of the Derm squads.  Head out there and hold them off.

Suit up in Light armor with a repair pack on this one.  You will need to cover some ground, so use the vehicle station to get a Mongoose or Dingo, whichever you prefer.

OK, saddle up!  I'll radio you with detailed objective info en route.

Good luck, Ransom.  Try not to get yourself killed."		Khanjar Zane	"Sit down, newbloods.  And don't look so shocked.  Your training is over.  It has been for weeks.  We've been pushing you through extra drills to sharpen your skills.

You are no longer cadets.  You are soldiers.  And now its time for you to prove it.

A little over seven hours ago, a BioDerm assault flotilla entered the system.  Right now, Derm reavers are dropping into key locations across Gamma Serpentis IV.  They think we're guarding something important here, something besides a bunch of steak-filled refrigerator crates.  We want them to continue to think that.

From the initial reports, it's clear we are vastly outnumbered.  Our plan is to hit the Derms hard and not give an inch.

Ransom!  I need you to volunteer for a solo mission!  There’s a small unoccupied base right in the path of one of the Derm squads.  Head out there and hold them off.

Suit up in Light armor with a repair pack on this one.  You will need to cover some ground, so use the vehicle station to get a Mongoose or Dingo, whichever you prefer.

OK, saddle up!  I'll radio you with detailed objective info en route.

Good luck, Ransom.  Try not to get yourself killed."
M06_INTRO	Acquire and board Mongoose or Dingo		Leut Donatan	"Leut Donatan here, Ransom.   Hop on a vehicle, and I’ll waypoint the destination base for you.  There's not much time."
M06_GO_TO_STATION			Leut Donatan	I'm not gonna tell you again.  Head for that vehicle station.  NOW!
M06_SCRUBBED			Leut Donatan	"Mission scrubbed.  I don't know what your problem is, but we can't count on you.  Return to base."
M06_GO_TO_BASE	Go to waypoint.		Leut Donatan	"OK, good.  Head for the waypointed base."
M06_TIME			Leut Donatan	"Time’s running out, get to that base right now!"
M06_FAIL			Leut Donatan	Mission failure.  We can't hold that perimeter now without losing a lot of lives.
M06_GO_TO_GEN	Fully repair generator at waypoint.		Leut Donatan	"OK, I’m waypointing the generator for you.  Get in there and repair it.  I'll mark the inventory stations once the gens are on-line."
M06_REPAIR_GEN			Leut Donatan	Make sure to repair that gen to full functionality
M06_GO_TO_TURRET	Fully repair base turrets at waypoints.		Leut Donatan	Good work.  Make sure both turrets are fully repaired.  They’re waypointed for you.
M06_REPAIR_TURRET			Leut Donatan	Repair both turrets to full capacity.
M06_SWAP_BARRELS	Install mortar barrels on base turrets at waypoints.		Leut Donatan	"OK.  You need to swap out those AA turret barrels for some mortar barrels.  Remember, you need to be in Medium or Heavy armor to deploy barrels."
M06_DEFEND_BASE	Defeat all inbound enemy forces.		Leut Donatan	The Derm force ought to be arriving soon.  Do whatever you need to do.  Hold that base!
M06_HANG_IN_THERE			Leut Donatan	"Hang in there, looks like another wave is moving in.  Take ‘em out."
M06_SUCCESS	Mission success.		Leut Donatan	"Great work out there, Ransom.  Don't relax too much.  There's a lot more to do."
M06_DEBRIEF	"~FFFFFF~Good job, Ransom.  The Derms weren't expecting resistance in that area.  They'll probably bring in reinforcements.  The more the merrier, eh?

Well, after that fight, you're no longer a newblood.  Consider yourself a blooded warrior now.  If you survive this, I expect you'll have more stories to tell than most veterans.  Not that it's any comfort right now.

All right, dismissed."		Leut Donatan	"Good job, Ransom.  The Derms weren't expecting resistance in that area.  They'll probably bring in reinforcements.  The more the merrier, eh?

Well, after that fight, you're no longer a newblood.  Consider yourself a blooded warrior now.  If you survive this, I expect you'll have more stories to tell than most veterans.  Not that it's any comfort right now.

All right, dismissed."
M07_BRIEFING	"~FFFFFF~We’re sending you out again, Ransom.

A strong Derm force has holed up in a bunker in Zeta 4, and we need to root them out before their reinforcements arrive.  We figure one soldier can slip through their perimeter while the rest of us make a loud and messy assault.  The turrets on the bunker's eastern approach will be under Derm control by now, so you'll come in from the west.

Infiltrate the base and destroy the generators powering those turrets.  In the meantime, we'll bring in Heavies from the east.  It's crucial that you take down those gens ASAP.  The Heavies are too slow to avoid the turret fire.  We're counting on you to move fast.  We lose more than three armors on the way in, then we scrub the entire mission.

We'll drop you in as close to the base as we can.  There's an inventory station near the drop zone.  Grab whatever loadout you need.

Move out, soldier."		Khanjar Zane	"We’re sending you out again, Ransom.

A strong Derm force has holed up in a bunker in Zeta 4, and we need to root them out before their reinforcements arrive.  We figure one soldier can slip through their perimeter while the rest of us make a loud and messy assault.  The turrets on the bunker's eastern approach will be under Derm control by now, so you'll come in from the west.

Infiltrate the base and destroy the generators powering those turrets.  In the meantime, we'll bring in Heavies from the east.  It's crucial that you take down those gens ASAP.  The Heavies are too slow to avoid the turret fire.  We're counting on you to move fast.  We lose more than three armors on the way in, then we scrub the entire mission.

We'll drop you in as close to the base as we can.  There's an inventory station near the drop zone.  Grab whatever loadout you need.

Move out, soldier."
M07_INTRO	Get loadout appropriate to infiltrate base and destroy generators.		Leut Donatan	"OK, get whatever you need and get to that base and take down those gens."
M07_BASE_WAYPOINT	"Go to waypointed base.
Locate and destroy generators."		Leut Donatan	I’ve got the base waypointed on your HUD.  Get busy.  There’s not much time.
M07_GET_MOVING			Khanjar Zane	"Yo, Ransom!  Get your butt in gear!"
M07_SCRUBBED			Khanjar Zane	"Leut, Ransom's moving erratically.  Figure something must have happened to him.  I recommend we scrub this mission."
M07_BASE_AHEAD			Leut Donatan	"Objective is waypointed, Ransom.  Base should be dead ahead.  Good luck."
M07_DESTROY_GEN			Leut Donatan	What’s keeping you?  Get those generators offline now!
M07_HEAVY_DESTROYED	Heavy armor destroyed.		Leut Donatan	Heavy armor destroyed.
M07_WE_ARE_IN			Leut Donatan	"Alright, Ransom.  We're in.  Derms are neutralized."
M07_WAY_TO_GO			Khanjar Zane	"Way to go, Ransom!"
M07_PULLING_BACK			Leut Donatan	Losses have exceeded acceptable levels.  We're pulling back.  No sense in wasting lives. 
M07_SUCCESS	Mission success.		Leut Donatan	Good work.  It looks like you and your squad were able to take out the enemy force.  Your relief is on the way.  Return to Fort Aquila for debriefing.
M07_DEBRIEF	"~FFFFFF~OK, hero.  Nice job, but don't rest on your laurels.

We've given the Derms plenty to chew on up here, but there are other hotspots where they've landed troops to set up a planetary beachhead.

We're sending you and a squad south to the Gebir-Varoth Parchlands, and I'll be going along for the ride.  The C.O. will hold the fort while we're gone.

Go pack your kit.  Transport lifts in thirty."		Khanjar Zane	"OK, hero.  Nice job, but don't rest on your laurels.

We've given the Derms plenty to chew on up here, but there are other hotspots where they've landed troops to set up a planetary beachhead.

We're sending you and a squad south to the Gebir-Varoth Parchlands.  The Leut and I are going along for the ride.  The C.O. will hold the fort while we're gone.

Go pack your kit.  Transport lifts in thirty."
M08_BRIEFING	"~FFFFFF~Hey, Ransom.  You look thirsty.  Hot out here in the Parchlands, huh?  Well, it's about to get hotter.  Leut says it's time to hit the Derms.

We're going to have you mortaring targets with a demolition squad.  Time to rain some serious heat on the enemy.

Suit up in Heavy armor.  You've got some mortaring to do.  We'll drop you close to the Derm base, which will be waypointed.  We'll send further orders once your squad hits the dirt.

Questions?  Good.  Get moving!"		Khanjar Zane	"Heya, Ransom.  You look thirsty.  Hot out here in the Parchlands, huh?  Well, it's about to get hotter.  Leut says it's time to hit the Derms.

We're gonna have you mortaring targets with a demolition squad.  Time to rain some serious heat on the enemy.

Suit up in Heavy armor.  You've got some mortaring to do.  We'll drop you close to the Derm base, which will be waypointed.  We'll send further orders once your squad hits the dirt.

Questions?  Good.  Get moving!"
M08_INTRO			Leut Donatan	"OK, Ransom.  Escort your squad to their positions.  Before we can send in some scouts to take the base, we need you to eliminate the defensive turrets."
M08_STAY_TOGETHER			Leut Donatan	"You need to stay with your squad, Ransom."
M08_DONT_WANDER			Leut Donatan	"I'm not going to tell you again, soldier.  Wandering off like that costs lives."
M08_SCRUBBED			Leut Donatan	That's it.  This mission is scrubbed.
M08_DESTROY_TURRET			Leut Donatan	"OK, squad leader.  I want you and your troops to take out the five base turrets around this outpost.  The target waypoints should appear in your HUD now."
M08_MOVE_OUT			Leut Donatan	"Let's move out, team!"
M08_TURRET_DESTROYED	Turret destroyed.		Leut Donatan	Turret destroyed.
M08_HEAVY_LOST			Leut Donatan	Allied Heavy armor destroyed.
M08_TERMINATED			Leut Donatan	"Mission terminated.  Soldier, I told you to protect your squadmates."
M08_HIT_SWITCH			Leut Donatan	"Listen up, Ransom.   The Derms surprised us.  Your reinforcements are pinned down in a firefight, so you have to step up on this one.  I’m now waypointing a new objective for you: the base control switch.  Follow the waypoint in and hit that switch.  Your armor's command codes will handle the rest.  Take out any Derms in your way.  Your Squad will move in and keep the remaining Derms busy."
M08_MOP_UP			Leut Donatan	Well done.  Now assist in the mop-up.  We should have this area secured shortly.
M08_FAIL			Leut Donatan	"Fall back.  The Derms are too much for us.  It's going to be a lot tougher for us now.  I had hoped you'd be successful, soldier, but you're still too green."
M08_SUCCESS			Leut Donatan	"Good job, as usual, Ransom.  We've got a transport on the way in to drop off your relief and bring you back to base camp.  Donatan out. "
M08_DEBRIEF	"~FFFFFF~Khanjar Zane is still out on patrol.

In a couple of hours, we're moving to hook up with a force at the Skanaskar Glacier in the southern mountain range.  The Derms are assembling the bulk of their strike force there.

The Sikkyn-Captain informed me a large mass of Derm troopships has exited the jumpgate.  They keep sending reinforcements to take whatever it is we're protecting here.  I wish I knew what that was.

Get some sleep, Ransom.  Someone will wake you when the transport arrives."		Leut Donatan	"Khanjar Zane is still out on patrol.

In a couple of hours, we're moving to hook up with a force at the Skanaskar Glacier in the southern mountain range.  The Derms are assembling the bulk of their strikeforce there.

The Sikkyn-Captain informed me a large mass of Derm troopships has exited the jumpgate.  They keep sending reinforcements to take whatever it is we're protecting here.  (chuckle)  I wish I knew what that was.

Get some sleep, Ransom.  Someone will wake you when the transport arrives."
M10_BRIEFING	"~FFFFFF~Good to see you looking rested, Ransom.  We’ve got another mission for you.

Our recent successes have allowed us a little breathing room.  That last dropship restocked our supplies and provided us with a Hammer bomber.  We'd like to use that bomber to send a message to the Derm.  A very unpleasant message.

Problem is, our bomber's objective is defended with enough firepower to swat the flyboys out of the sky before they can drop their payload.

You are to take a Mongoose and rendezvous with a fire team we have in position.  Together you will beat a clear path for a bombing run.

Keep in mind, you are operating under severe time constraints.  We need to get that bomber in quickly, so you must work fast to take out those AA turrets."		Leut Donatan	"Good to see you looking rested, Ransom.  We’ve got another mission for you.

Our recent successes have allowed us a little breathing room.  That last dropship restocked our supplies and provided us with a Hammer bomber.  We'd like to use that bomber to send a message to the Derm.  A very unpleasant message.

Problem is, our bomber's objective is defended with enough firepower to swat the flyboys out of the sky before they can drop their payload.

You are to take a Mongoose and rendezvous with a fire team we have in position.  Together you will beat a clear path for a bombing run.

Keep in mind, you are operating under severe time constraints.  We need to get that bomber in quickly, so you must work fast to take out those AA turrets."
M10_INTRO			Leut Donatan	Ready for us to bomb these Derms into oblivion?  Grab a Mongoose and head for the waypoint I’ve set in your HUD.  The assault team is waiting for you there.
M10_WHY_WAIT			Leut Donatan	Well?  What are you waiting for?
M10_ON_OWN			Leut Donatan	"Bad news, Ransom.  We lost the assault team you were supposed to hook up with.  You're on your own.  I still need you to take out all the turrets around the target base.  Fortunately, the assault team managed to set up an inventory station before the Derms ambushed them, so I suggest getting a missile launcher.  Once those turrets are down, get out of the bomber's way and await further orders."
M10_BOMBER_LOST			Leut Donatan	"Mission failed.  Our bird went down without laying its eggs.  Return to base camp, soldier."
M10_NO_BOMBER			Leut Donatan	"Forget it, Ransom.  I've scrapped the bombing run.  Return to base."
M10_GO_TO_SWITCH			Leut Donatan	"OK, Ransom.  The assault team was supposed to penetrate that base and hit the control switch.  I’ll waypoint it for you.  Hit the switch and secure the area.  Eliminate any remaining enemy assets."
M10_GET_GOING			Leut Donatan	I’m not gonna tell you again.  Get a vehicle and get going.  NOW!
M10_SCRUBBED			Leut Donatan	"What is your problem, soldier? Mission Scrubbed!"
M10_GO_TO_MARK			Leut Donatan	Your destination is waypointed. Get going!
M10_INCOMING			Leut Donatan	Bomber on final approach.  Get clear of the base.  I repeat: Bomber on approach!
M10_SUCCESS			Leut Donatan	"Good work, Ransom.  Head back to base, on the double."
M10_GET_SWITCH			Leut Donatan	"Retake that switch, Ransom!"
M10_DEBRIEF	"~FFFFFF~We've denied another base to the enemy, but we've got other problems.  Communications are garbled on all channels.  Something strange is happening.  Our transport pilots report readings of EMP detonations to the north, and when they go above the cloud cover, they report unusual flashes way up in the atmosphere.  Weird.

Anyway, get some sleep.  I have a feeling things are heating up big-time.  Be ready."		Khanjar Zane	"We've denied another base to the enemy, but we've got other problems.  Communications are garbled on all channels.  Something strange is happening.  Our transport pilots report readings of EMP detonations to the north, and when they go above the cloud cover, they report unusual flashes way up in the atmosphere.  Weird.

Anyway, get some sleep.  I have a feeling things are heating up big-time.  Be ready."
M11_BRIEFING	"~FFFFFF~Good news, Ransom!  Commlinks are back online.  Fury is here!  It's her ships pounding the Derms in orbit.  Don't ask me how she got here so fast.

The orbital battle is swinging our way, but it's still at a critical point. Sure, we've been making headway down here, but now Command is worried about the Derms escaping.

So here's the deal: you and a Heavy squad will be dropped at a small base on the far end of the glacier. The generators in that base power critical relays for maintaining the orbital tracking sensor network in this hemisphere.  Fury needs them to stay online if she's going to wrap up the Derm taskforce.

Your mission is to protect the generators until we can mobilize a larger force.  This is strictly a defensive mission.  You’ll find an inventory station very close to the objective.  Do whatever you have to, but under no circumstances may those gens go offline.  Do you understand me?  Under no circumstances!"		Khanjar Zane	"Good news, Ransom!  Commlinks are back online.  Fury is here!  It's her ships pounding the Derms in orbit.  Don't ask me how she got here so fast.

The orbital battle is swinging our way, but it's still at a critical point. Sure, we've been making headway down here, but now Command is worried about the Derms escaping.

So here's the deal: you and a Heavy squad will be dropped at a small base on the far end of the glacier. The generators in that base power critical relays for maintaining the orbital tracking sensor network in this hemisphere.  Fury needs them to stay online if she's going to wrap up the Derm taskforce.

Your mission is to protect the generators until we can mobilize a larger force.  This is strictly a defensive mission.  You’ll find an inventory station very close to the objective.  Do whatever you have to, but under no circumstances may those gens go offline.  Do you understand me?  Under NO circumstances!"
M11_INTRO			Leut Donatan	"Hold that room until the reinforcements arrive.  Don’t be a cowboy, Ransom.  Stick close to those gens.  Alright.  Good luck."
M11_DEFEND_GEN			Leut Donatan	"Defend those gens, Ransom!"
M11_GO_TO_GEN			Leut Donatan	Stay near those generators.  Return to your post immediately!
M11_ENEMY_COMING			Leut Donatan	Enemy units approaching.
M11_BATTLE_STATIONS			Leut Donatan	Enemy in base.  Get ready!
M11_FAIL			Leut Donatan	I wasn’t kidding about those generators. You just cost us that base and compromised our entire operation.  Mission failed.
M11_GEN_ONLINE			Leut Donatan	Generator back online.
M11_MORE_ENEMY			Leut Donatan	Sensors indicate enemy transport approaching.  This one's not over yet!
M11_GEN_LOST			Leut Donatan	"One generator down.  Fix it if you can, but do not, I repeat, DO NOT let that other gen go down."
M11_EVEN_MORE_ENEMY			Leut Donatan	"Another enemy transport approaching.  Hold the line, Ransom."
M11_FAIL_GENS_LOST			Leut Donatan	Generators lost.  Mission failed.
M11_STAY_AT_GEN			Leut Donatan	"Leave those gens again, soldier, and I'll personally feed you to an Ymirian razor-hag!"
M11_SUCCESS			Leut Donatan	"Reinforcements in place.  Orbital sensors status is all green.  Outstanding work, Ransom.  Keep this up, and you'll leave Gamma Serpentis IV with a commission."
M11_DEBRIEF	"~FFFFFF~Nice work keeping those generators up, Ransom.  Have a seat.

I'm sorry to tell you Khanjar Zane was a casualty of the day's fighting.  The Derms hit her squad's position hard, and we had to run a fast evac.  She was holding the enemy off when a mortar round came in.  She died instantly.  She will be missed.

I know she had developed great respect for you.  That is why I am promoting you to Khanjar in her place.  You have come through a trial of fire and you deserve the honor.

We're being ordered back to the Parchlands.  There's a large BioDerm force rallying there, and we're being given the honor of spearheading the assault on their position.  Rest assured there will be other honors when this is all over.

Get some sleep.  There's still work to do."		Leut Donatan	"Nice work keeping those generators up, Ransom.  Have a seat.

I'm sorry to tell you Khanjar Zane was a casualty of the day's fighting.  The Derms hit her squad's position hard, and we had to run a fast evac.  She was holding the enemy off when a mortar round came in.  She died instantly.  She will be missed.

I know she had developed great respect for you.  That is why I am promoting you to Khanjar in her place.  You have come through a trial of fire and you deserve the honor.

We're being ordered back to the Parchlands.  There's a large BioDerm force rallying there, and we're being given the honor of spearheading the assault on their position.  Rest assured there will be other honors when this is all over.

Get some sleep.  There's still work to do."
M13_BRIEFING	"~FFFFFF~There you are, Khanjar.  You're holding up well.  After the glacier, I thought I'd welcome the desert, but this is a furnace.  Glad to see the heat isn't bothering you much.

Your mission today is simple: follow the waypoint to the base, kill the enemy, hit the control switch.  Any questions?

The Sirdar-Prime herself will be monitoring this operation over the Command Circuit.  Don't embarrass us, Ransom.  Not that I expect you will.

By the way, we don't need prisoners.  I think we're all ready to deliver some payback for the loss of Khanjar Zane and other comrades.  The holdouts you'll face today deserve no mercy.  Don't show them any.

Good luck."		Leut Donatan	"There you are, Khanjar.  You're holding up well.  After the glacier, I thought I'd welcome the desert, but this is a furnace.  Glad to see the heat isn't bothering you much.

Your mission today is simple: follow the waypoint to the base, kill the enemy, hit the control switch.  Any questions?

The Sirdar-Prime herself will be monitoring this operation over the Command Circuit.  Don't embarrass us, Ransom.  Not that I expect you will.

By the way, we don't need prisoners.  I think we're all ready to deliver some payback for the loss of Khanjar Zane and other comrades.  The holdouts you'll face today deserve no mercy.  Don't show them any.

Good luck."
M13_INTRO			Sirdar-Prime Fury	"This is Sirdar-Prime Fury.  You have your orders, Khanjar Ransom.  Wipe them out."
M13_STAY_TOGETHER			Leut Donatan	"Stay with your unit, Khanjar."
M13_KEEP_IT_UP			Leut Donatan	"Keep it up, Ransom.  Looking good so far."
M13_HIT_SWITCH			Leut Donatan	Beautiful.  The Sirdar-Prime is impressed.  Now hit that switch and finish this.
M13_BYE			Leut Donatan	"We can't get a medivac there in time.  Goodbye, Khanjar."
M13_GO_TO_UNIT			Leut Donatan	What did I tell you?  Get back to your unit.  NOW!
M13_FAIL			Leut Donatan	Mission failed.
M13_KICK_ASS			Leut Donatan	"Alright, let’s get in there and take care of business!"
M13_SUCCESS			Leut Donatan	"It's been an honor to fight alongside you, Khanjar Jarak Ransom.  I hope to do so again in the future.  In the meantime, get cleaned up.  A shuttle is on the way down.  I believe it's Fury herself, coming to honor us.  I'll talk to you later, Khanjar.  Congratulations! "
M13_DEBRIEF	"~FFFFFF~Khanjar Jarak Ransom: By the authority vested in me by the Blood Eagle tribe and by the United Tribal Pact, I hereby award you the Paragon Cross, for courage and heroism beyond the pale.  Let your example shine forth in these dark times and inspire the Tribes to victory.

I foresee great things ahead for you, young Ransom.  But for now, we'll take one victory at a time, eh?  Well done!"		Sirdar-Prime Fury	"Khanjar Jarek Ransom: By the authority vested in me by the Blood Eagle tribe and by the United Tribal Pact, I hereby award you the Paragon Cross, for courage and heroism beyond the pale.  Let your example shine forth in these dark times and inspire the Tribes to victory.

I foresee great things ahead for you, young Ransom.  But for now, we'll take one victory at a time, eh?  Well done!"
				
