T1	"~FFFFFF~Personal Log
N’garai al-Mansur of Halakar Blood
Sikkyn-Captain, Blood Eagle Tribe
6th day Barbed Knife, 3945
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~Word came yesterday of another indecisive clash with the Hordes, this time in the Peredur system.  Heavy losses were sustained on both sides.  We can't take much more of this.  The BioDerms are bleeding us to death.  We need to draw them out, make them commit to a time and place of our choosing.  And we need to do it soon.

The Sirdar-Prime has a plan.  As with her other stratagems, it is a gamble, and it makes me uneasy, but it might catch the Hordes off-guard.  I am close to grasping at straws right now, so I will undertake this operation as the Sirdar-Prime asks.

I am taking command of the garrison at Gamma Serpentis IV, a sparsely populated world with a variety of terrain, used now primarily for training newblood soldiers for the war.

The cadres should be arriving shortly after I do.  For ""accelerated training.""

God help them."	
T2	"~FFFFFF~Quantum-Reed Transmission
8th day Barbed Knife, 3945
To: Hammer
From: Anvil
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~The Halakar have done a superior job keeping details of this place hidden.

Gamma Serpentis IV is an ideal location for the plan.  The population is very sparse, most of it consisting of the Unitech mining employees and garrison support personnel.  We won’t have to worry about widespread civilian casualties, so however this turns out, it won’t be a mass slaughter like Ymir.

The key base facilities lie on terrain that is perfectly suited for modern hit-and-run defensive operations.  We should have the home field advantage, at least until the enemy gets ground truth intel.  Further, the training purposes of most of these bases mean they are currently unoccupied and understated in our own asset estimates.  The enemy won’t know exactly what we’ve got here, so their objective selection will be hit-and-miss in terms of effectiveness.

I see why you wanted me to come here."	
T3	"~FFFFFF~Personal Log
N’garai al-Mansur of Halakar Blood
Sikkyn-Captain, Blood Eagle Tribe
14th day Barbed Knife, 3945
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~I have ordered Leut Donatan to push the recruits hard.  Very hard.  I want our newbloods to sweat blood before they're done.  I want them pushed to their limits and beyond.  Our survival depends on how quickly we can field new and competent warriors.

That is especially true here.

I got a look at our local cadre here at Fort Aquila today.  A scruffy, hard-looking lot.  I understand we’ve dragged a number of them out of the underworld, with at least one being a pit-fighter Jensir Halakar pulled from the cesspools of Bira Marduk’s shadow slums.  I suppose we can’t be too picky with our raw material.

I hope they are as tough as they look.  I’ve spoken with Leut Donatan and Khanjar Zane about the accelerated training, and I approve.  These newbloods are being run through the highest level of elite training the UTP can provide, and even a notch up from that.  I’m not certain I’d stand up to it, were I a young newblood.

The training supervisors impress me.  Patamir Donatan is quiet, analytical, much like myself.  Varda Zane is a pistol, like all the Khanjars I’ve ever met.  I had to suppress a smile at her tongue-lashing of the newbloods on the first day.  It brought back memories.

~FFFFFF~Command Circuit Transmission
From: Sikkyn-Captain al-Mansur
To: Leut Donatan
Copy: Khanjar Zane
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~On another subject, I'm expecting a large number of crates delivered from off-world over the next few weeks.  Please detach the necessary personnel to unload these.  I believe the newbloods would do well to supplement the garrison shifts.  Put every available soldier on duty guarding these crates, from the time they are unloaded from the drop ship until they are safely in storage.  After they are in storage, post a heavy guard and detach a pair of Dingoes for round-the-clock air patrols.  I expect the highest security.  Send me your plan once you’ve worked out the details.

Al-Mansur out."	
T4	"~FFFFFF~Quantum-Reed Transmission
2nd day Shadowed Suns, 3945
To: Hammer
From: Anvil
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~Ships began to arrive with the shipments.  In-system traffic has risen tenfold in the last three days.  There are shuttles flying day and night, dropping crates at the various training and garrison nodes around the planet.  Our people are exhausted from moving everything, but they’re taking it very seriously.  Naturally, their curiosity has been awakened.  We even hired some off-duty miners to provide extra labor.  I’m sure the whispers are reaching the right ears."	
T5	"~FFFFFF~Quantum-Reed Transmission
11th day Shadowed Suns, 3945
To: Anvil
From: Hammer
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~Good work.  We’ve had some small success in clearing the Hordes off Hellbricht Station.  They didn’t leave much behind that was recognizable, especially their prisoners.  The naval assets we shifted to the Hellbricht system leave an under defended jump gate thread to Gamma Serpentis.  I hope your newbloods will be ready.

~FFFFFF~Quantum-Reed Transmission
11th day Shadowed Suns, 3945
To: Hammer
From: Anvil
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~Indeed.  They’re showing excellent progress.  We’re advancing their training to the next phase."	
M01	"~FFFFFF~Command Circuit Transmission
From: Sikkyn-Captain al-Mansur
To: Leut Donatan
Copy: Khanjar Zane
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~I’m pleased by your results.  The newbloods are weathering the training better than expected.  Only four deaths here at Fort Aquila.  That’s substantially better than the other training camps are doing.  Given what we’re putting the cadre through, that’s not bad at all.

Proceed directly to second-stage combat simulation.  Make sure the V-Suit mods are dialed to inflict maximum pain when the wearer is “hit.”  Increase the dosage of neurostim drugs during the orientation sessions.  Our medical officer assures me we’re still within acceptable parameters.  Still, keep an eye out for any indication of psychological degeneration.  Having our newbloods go mad would be bad for morale.

Speaking of morale, let's begin to encourage some real competition among our trainees.  Khanjar, I leave it to you to choose the carrot and the stick.

Al-Mansur out."	
M02	"~FFFFFF~Quantum-Reed Transmission
18th day Shadowed Suns, 3945
To: Anvil
From: Hammer
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~No sign of the fish yet.  We’re running our training program at the redline.  Two more newbloods burned out yesterday, making six for the last ten days.  However, most of our original hundred are adapting well.  We even have a few standouts.  I hope they’re ready in time.  We’ve doubled our efforts to ""guard"" the crates, and are following your instructions regarding placement of the explosives."	
M03	"~FFFFFF~Quantum-Reed Transmission
2nd day Jaguar's Hunt, 3945
To: Anvil
From: Hammer
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~The fish just passed through Hidalgo system, right on schedule.  It's a big fish, but not so big we can’t handle it with the forces we’ve mustered.  You’ll have to set the hook.  If we come in-system too quickly, the fish will escape.  We need it to commit itself to the bait before we arrive.

I’m sorry your people have to take the hit.  If there were any other avenue, I'd pursue it.

~FFFFFF~Quantum-Reed Transmission
2nd day Jaguar's Hunt, 3945
To: Hammer
From: Anvil
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~Understood.  That puts ETA for the fish at about six days.  We’ll be ready.

~FFFFFF~Command Circuit Transmission
From: Sikkyn-Captain al-Mansur
To: Leut Donatan
Copy: Khanjar Zane
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~Give your standout newbloods some R and R.  They’ll need it.  Go easier on the others, but not too easy.  If all goes as planned, things will be heating up for your crew soon enough.  We need to be prepared.

Al-Mansur out."	
M04	"~FFFFFF~Personal Log
N’garai al-Mansur of Halakar Blood
Sikkyn-Captain, Blood Eagle Tribe
6th day Jaguar's Hunt, 3945
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~One of our newbloods lost his mind today.  Halvorson.

I reviewed the combat recording.  It happened during the Hunters exercise.  He had almost reached the Nexus when someone knocked him down with a well-timed virtual spinfusor hit.  He landed and let out a bloodcurdling scream.  His armor locked up to protect him from the fall and give him a timeout before letting him back into the game.  He hasn’t stopped screaming since.  The medical officer has him heavily sedated, but the neurostim has Halvorson’s brain chemistry simmering like a pot of klef-deer gumbo; it makes effective sedation almost impossible.  The diagnosis is hyperacute claustrophobic psychosis, and the prognosis is bad.

If Halvorson’s lucky, he’ll simply become autistic.  If not, he’ll scream out the rest of his days under heavy restraints.

The other newbloods were shaken, but they didn’t understand what really happened.  We haven’t told them about the neurostim.  I’ve ordered the medical officer to back down the dosage until he’s completed physicals on the entire cadre."	
M05	"~FFFFFF~Quantum-Reed Transmission
7th day Jaguar's Hunt, 3945
To: Hammer
From: Anvil
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~Look alive out there, my friend.  The fish has taken the bait and is on the way out for a visit."	
M06	"~FFFFFF~Command Circuit Transmission
~FFFF00~*** PRIORITY OVERRIDE ***
~FFFFFF~From: Sikkyn-Captain al-Mansur
To: Leut Donatan, Khanjar Zane
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~Go to Code Red and scramble all units.  We have a large number of bogeys in-system, and our picket corvette had to light up its X-R drive and punch into an outbound slow-warp.

We’ll have visitors soon.  Prime the charges, but until I give the word, deploy hardshells to the crate locations.  You’ll handle local tactical operations; my hands are full coordinating with our other bases.  Good luck.

Al-Mansur out."	
M07	"~FFFFFF~Quantum-Reed Transmission
9th day Jaguar’s Hunt, 3945
To: Hammer
From: Anvil
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~The fish has taken the bait in a big way.  We’re outnumbered about five to one, near as I can tell, and there are still Horde drop ships in orbit.  One of our newbloods held off a Derm incursion single-handedly while we fought off an attack on Stack A.  The miners at M-Falls haven’t been hit yet, but the settlement at Godoshen was wiped out by a sub-horde within hours of the Derms hitting the Gamma Serpentis IV envelope.

We’re going to hang on as long as we can, then relocate to secondary bases at the unoccupied training facilities.

Don’t let our lives be wasted."	
M08	"~FFFFFF~Quantum-Reed Transmission
15th day Jaguar’s Hunt, 3945
To: Hammer
From: Anvil
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~Where in the starry hells did the Halakar fish this Jarak Ransom from?  He’s the pit-fighter newblood, you may recall, and one of our standouts during the training, but he has emerged as a Derm-killing machine.  It’s lifted the morale of the other newbloods, I can tell you.

Otherwise, we’ll be abandoning Fort Aquila soon.  Too many of the enemy, and we can’t afford to stand up to a full-fledged offensive.  The micronuke charges are set.  When we leave, we’ll leave with a bang."	
M09	"~FFFFFF~Personal Log
N’garai al-Mansur of Halakar Blood
Sikkyn-Captain, Blood Eagle Tribe
1st day Eagle’s Oath, 3945
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~We abandoned Fort Aquila last night.  Against my wishes, Sergeant Arzat stayed behind to lure the Derms in and make sure the charges went off for maximum effect.  This morning, we can still see the resulting plume of smoke and dust from our base camp in the hills.  The Derms don’t realize how saturated this region is with small bases and hidden bunkers.  The Halakar and the Nagashima before them used Gamma Serpentis IV as a last-ditch rallying point where they could go to ground.  Their paranoia is serving us well now.

I wish I could feel optimistic.  The Derms have landed around the planet in substantial force.  They seem to have swallowed the idea that we detonated the crates to prevent them from finding out what was in them, so they’re scouring everything in search of a knowledgeable prisoner or other clues as to what we’ve been up to.  Have to admire their bloody-mindedness.

Donatan’s group succeeded in stirring the hornet’s nest down in the Parchlands.  I’ve ordered them to the Skanaskar Glacier region in the southern polar zone.  The Derms have concentrated too much strength in the desert.  A successful offensive at Skanaskar may spread them out and leave them more vulnerable when the trap is sprung.

If Fury doesn’t get here soon, we’re finished."	
M10	"~FFFFFF~Encrypted Radio Transmission
10th day Eagle’s Oath, 3945
To: Sikkyn-Captain al-Mansur
From: Fury
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~Don’t bother trying to respond to this.  The Derms might triangulate on an off world squirt, and we’re about to put a few dozen EMP salvos into the upper atmosphere.

We are in-system, N’garai.  Tell your people to hang on.  I’ll send another message -- fire tubes one through six, Ensign -- later.  It’s a bit hot up here right now.

~FFFFFF~Command Circuit Transmission
From: Sikkyn-Captain al-Mansur
To: Leut Donatan
Copy: Khanjar Zane
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~Hit the Derms now and hit them hard.  Their orbital presence is busy being vaporized.  Let’s take advantage of the chaos.

I have a job for your prodigy Ransom.  Fury has patched into a laser array of groundside sensors that let her ships target Horde vessels with active sensors despite the EMP interference.  The Derms will figure this out fast enough.  They’re not stupid.  Put Ransom in charge of a fire team to hold the linchpin generators powering that sensor array.  It’ll help our flyboys dispatch the enemy that much faster.

Al-Mansur out."	
M11	"~FFFFFF~Personal Log
N’garai al-Mansur of Halakar Blood
Sikkyn-Captain, Blood Eagle Tribe
12th day Eagle’s Oath, 3945
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~We lost Khanjar Zane.  She’ll be missed.  So many have died to stage this elaborate trap, but all indications are that the sacrifice was worth it.  The Derms committed an enormous strike force, and we were finally able to come to grips with them on terms where we could score a decisive victory.  From here on, it’s mop-up.  Troop morale is up, whereas the Derms have shifted to a more desperate defense.  They’re not fighting to win any longer, just to survive.  Now they’re cornered animals.  We may have the victory secured, but there are still hundreds, if not thousands, of raging, heavily armed enemy soldiers to deal with.

Ransom completed his mission in exemplary fashion.  I’ve ordered him promoted.  He’ll fill Zane’s place well, I think."	
	"~FFFFFF~Radio Transmission
17th day Eagle’s Oath, 3945
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
~AAAAFF~This is Fury.  The enemy has been neutralized.  We have taken prisoners.  We have captured ships.  We have achieved an impressive victory.  We have stopped the Horde war machine in its bloody tracks.

Good work, all.  I’m proud of you.  Today humanity has stood firm and struck a blow against an enemy that seeks the obliteration of our species.

There were many heroes in this battle.  We shall not forget our dead.  Honor them even as we honor living heroes such as Khanjar Jarak Ransom and Leut Patamir Donatan.

Honor yourselves, but remember there are many battles yet to come.

Tonight, however -- speaking from shipboard time -- let us celebrate."
